Come in.
进来
Captain.
队长
We've applied
我们去申请了
to view the records of Family Hua.
南京对华家的审查记录
But failed.
没申请到
The Party Investigation Dept. refused.
党务调查科的人不肯给
Exactly.
是
They don't care us.
人家不买我们的账
In private,
私底下
I only get the message that
我只打探到这点儿消息
the second son of Family Hua called Hua Zhen
次子华桢
arrived in Shanghai and visited his friend
于邓铭远被捕第三日
the 3rd day when Deng Mingyuan had been arrested.
前往上海访友游玩
Is Hua Zhen in Shanghai?
华桢来上海了
It is said so.
对方是这么说的
When will he go back to Nanjing?
回南京的日期呢
I heard that he hadn't been back yet.
听说 还没回去
He just got home from Jiangyin,
刚从江阴回家
and soon went to Shanghai.
不久又去上海
And right on the 3rd day
而且还是在
when I arrested Deng Mingyuan.
我逮捕邓铭远的第三天
On the day I arrested Deng Mingyuan,
那天我逮捕
it seemed that Hua Zhen
邓铭远的时候
was the one who talked to him
在房间里跟他谈话的
in the room.
好像就是华桢
His father Hua Zhuoqin
父亲华卓钦
attended
早年就读于
Army University in Baoding
保定陆军速成学堂
and then studied abroad in Japan's Zhen Wu School.
后赴日入振武学堂
He was the classmate of the Chairman Jiang.
曾与蒋委员长同窗
He is the undersecretary of Military Affairs Department now.
现为军政部中将次长
Hua Zhen's elder brother called Hua Liang.
长兄华梁
In 1923,
民国十二年
he joined the soldier company of teaching battalion.
参加教导营学兵连
In 1924,
民国十三年
he was admitted to Whampoa Military Academy.
考入黄埔军校
Hua Zhen,
华桢
in 1931,
民国二十年
was admitted to the Class Zhengze
考入陆军大学
in Army University.
正则班
He is the best student in subjects like
兵器学 物理 外语
armament science, physics and foreign language.
成绩为同期生中最优
In 1935,
二十四年
he was chosen to be the second-year student
由电雷学校遴选入
of navigation science major in the S.M.C.
该校第二期航海科
You're a nice drawer.
画得真好
The scale here
这个地方的比例
is still a little off.
还是差一点儿
What's its name?
这叫什么号来着
Yet Sen Cruiser
逸仙号轻巡洋舰
and Gunboat.
扩大型炮舰
What's this
这个地方
used for?
是用来干什么的
What do you think?
你觉得呢
I think you must have partners
我觉得你在上海
in Shanghai.
肯定还是有同党的
We're done
我们今天
talking about it today.
就不聊这个话题了
Let's change a topic
我们呢
this time.
今天换个话题
I heard that
我听说
Hua Zhen,
军政部华次长的二公子
the second son of Undersecretary Hua of Military Affairs Department,
华桢
has been calling you teacher.
一直称呼你为老师
I've invested that
我查过了
the relationship between you two
华桢跟你的来往
is not very close.
其实并不是很多
You didn't receive the invitation
那天你根本就没有接到
of Family Hua at all.
华家的邀请函
It's a lie
所谓进入华家
that congratulating the Undersecretary Hua
是为了给华次长贺寿
on his birthday.
纯属鬼话
You want to escape
你是为了脱身
or you think
或者说你认为
someone in that house
那栋房子里
can help you escape.
有人可以帮你脱身
Who is that person?
谁啊
Why don't you ask Undersecretary Hua?
你为何不亲自问华次长
I will.
我会亲自去问的
Since you had been in Hua's house,
你进了华家
I'll certainly investigate Family Hua.
我就一定会调查华家
Captain Wei,
魏队长
I want to change the topic, too.
今天我也想换一个话题
A friend of mine
我有一个老朋友
had been in
以前
the military unit of investigation section
在南昌行营
in Nanchang Police Department.
调查科军事股
He had said that
如果不是因为
if the Nanchang Airport hadn't a fire
南昌机场失火
and the investigation section hadn't been dissolved,
调查科被迫解散
one of the Majors
他说
would be
当时有一位少校股
a Lieutenant Colonel now.
如今应该已经成为中校
Isn't Wei Fulai,
魏福来
your former name?
魏队长以前
Captain Wei.
是叫这个名字吧
What're you talking about?
你在说什么呀
I don't understand.
我听不懂
Wei Daiqing.
魏岱擎
You had made a good name
魏队长给自己起了一个
for yourself.
青云直上的好名字
You even want to investigate the Undersecretary of Military Affairs Department.
连军政部次长都想调查
Does the Garrison Command
魏队长这么大的野心
know your wild ambition?
警备司令部知道吗
This is not ambition.
这不叫野心
It's the responsibility
那是一个身为军人的
of a soldier.
责任心
But a traitor like you
像你这样的叛徒
will never understand.
是不会理解的
Prepare more charcoal pencils for Mr. Deng.
给邓组长多备点儿炭笔
He will stay here
看来他是要在我们这儿
for a longer time.
多留一段时日了
Miss Luo,
骆警官
how is your first day at work?
第一天上班感觉怎么样
Perfect.
好极了
The neighbors
以后咱们街坊邻里
will ask you for help
有什么事儿
in the future.
可都指着你了
No problem.
没问题
Brother.
哥
What happened?
这怎么了
The punks came again.
那群混混又来了
They said brother didn't settle the interests,
说哥还有利息没还清
and ruined our dinner.
这一桌子晚饭全掀了
Let me.
我来
I can do this.
你别沾手了
Sorry, Minmin.
珉敏 对不起啊
I can't offer you a dinner
你第一天当警察下班
after your first day home
回来连口热乎饭
as a police officer from work.
都没吃上
Brother,
哥
I'm the police now.
我现在已经是警察了
If they came again,
如果他们再敢过来
I'll report to the Fourth Station House.
我就去告诉四所
My colleagues take good care of me.
四所的人都特别照顾我
We'll all come to
到时候大家
our photo shop together
一起穿着警服
in our police uniforms.
来我们照相馆
We'll see who dares
到时候再看
to make trouble here again.
还有谁敢过来闹事
I'll find some food
我 我再去厨房看看
in the kitchen.
看看还能有什么吃的
Don't use your hand.
别用手了
Sister,
姐
you've polished it for half an hour.
你擦了半个小时了
What do you want to do?
你想干吗
Leave me alone.
你管我
I'm cleaning my own clothes.
我的衣服我就要擦
It's new.
人家是件新衣服
And you clean too much.
你都快把它给擦没了
Do your homework.
写你的作业吧
Sister,
姐
I wonder
我一直想问你
why you're obsessed with
为什么这么执着
being the police?
要当警察
Our captain said
我们队长说了
upholding the justice and protecting people.
匡扶正义 保护百姓
Do you want to
你是不是想拿这身警服
scare away the punks
吓跑那些
who bully brother?
欺负哥哥的坏人
Do you think
你以为我跟你一样
I'm a naive primary school student
小学生
like you?
那么幼稚
Will you
你不会还想把它
hang it before the door
挂在门口
and tell everyone.
昭告天下吧
Maybe it works.
说不定还真有用
Go to finish your homework.
写你作业去
You said that your colleagues
不过之前你说
will help us.
四所的人会来帮咱们
Are they saying that just for comforting
是不是为了
father and brother?
安慰爸和哥的
They aren't.
当然不是了
They all take care of me,
四所的人都可照顾我了
and they're willing to help me.
肯定会帮我的
Won't you be dismissed
你不会过几天
after a few days?
就被辞掉吧
No way.
怎么可能
How could they dismiss me?
怎么可能被辞掉
I'm the only policewoman in the Fourth Station House.
四所就我一个女警察
They all like me.
稀罕我还来不及呢
You are in charge of serving water,
你就负责端个茶倒个水
welcoming people and seeing them off.
迎来送往什么的
Going out is a waste of food.
出警浪费粮食
I heard that every policeman
我听说警察
has a partner.
都会配个搭档
Do you have one?
他们有给你配搭档吗
Sure.
当然有了
You're always in the last place.
你每次都考最后一名
Does your partner despise you?
你那搭档没嫌弃你
Despise me?
嫌弃我
He appreciates me very much.
他可喜欢我了
And we make
我们在一起配合
a perfect match.
那就是天衣无缝
You're lying.
一看就是骗人
If possible,
如果有可能
I advise you
我建议你
to change a partner.
尽快换一个搭档
This is for you.
送给你了
I've said that
我就说吧
it matches me.
还是我戴起来最好看
That's because I'm a policewoman now.
那是因为我当警察了
And I don't have chance to wear it.
戴不上
Thank you, sister.
谢谢姐姐
From the alarm service record,
从接警记录来看
the captain called Chen Hao
那个叫陈浩的警察队长
happened to appear
应该是在抓犯人的时候
when arresting the criminal.
碰巧出现
But when I was talking to him today,
可是今天我跟他说话
I found that he was
我发现他很反感
adverse to me as a policeman here.
我到四所当警察
So,
这么说
maybe he had done something illegal
他可能也做了坏事儿
and was afraid of being found out.
害怕被你发现
Maybe it's just an excuse
不排除他去文华饭店
of catching the suspect in the abduction case
追诱拐案嫌疑人
in Van Hwa Hotel.
只是个幌子
It's worth mentioning that
好在你父母的案子
the case involved in your parents
四所已经立了案
had been filing by the Fourth Station House.
目击者也是四所
And the witness is the suspect being investigated.
正在追查的嫌疑人
I've been the right place.
我没有来错地方
Brother Yuansheng,
远生哥哥
thank you for buying clothes for me.
谢谢你给我买的衣服
It seemed that the clothes I bought
我给你买的衣服
didn't fit.
是不是太大了
It doesn't matter.
没关系
I'm shorter than my peers.
是我个子本来就有点小
Just hang in there a little longer.
再坚持一下吧
If it goes well,
如果顺利的话
the case will be clear
用不了一个月
within a month.
案子就能查清楚
At that time,
到时候
you don't need to hide.
你也不用再躲躲藏藏
And I'll leave
我也可以离开
the mixed place.
那个烂泥潭了
Excuse me, Mr. Bai,
打扰了 白警官
is there a break room
请问我们四所
for a policewoman?
有没有女警休息室
We don't have policewoman.
四所也没有女警啊
Oh, you are.
把你给忘了
Let me explain,
是这样
if we don't pay you salary
这个月要是不给你
this month,
发薪水的话呢
we'll arrange a break room for you.
能给你安排个休息室
Do you choose salary
你是要薪水
or a break room?
还是要休息室
The salary.
要薪水
OK.
那行
Good morning.
早上好
Mr. Xiang, Miss Luo
向警官 骆警官
Don't you buy daily outfit
昨天队长让你买的便服
the captain asked?
买了没有
No.
没有买
I brought some from home.
我就从家里带了点儿
Did you buy?
你买了吗
I bought some.
买了好几套
Tell me if you need.
你要是有需要你跟我说
OK.
行
What's the matter?
啥情况
She's a girl.
女孩儿
You get off clothes before her.
你脱这么快你这
It's impolite.
不合适
I have not noticed.
我没注意到
Yuansheng,
远生
you have a nice watch.
你这表不错呀
Does your family run a business?
家里做小生意的
No.
不是
Don't be shy about it.
没什么不能说的
My father is
我爸
the boss of Hong Fa restaurant.
鸿发酒楼老板
My uncle is the sworn brother
我舅跟第五保的王保长
of director Wang in the 5th district.
又是结拜亲兄弟
We have real estate
家里在南市有几个地方
to charge rents in the south of the city.
可以收收租子什么的
I should keep it a secret
我这个条件
for my family.
才应该藏着掖着呢
But I don't care.
那我都无所谓了
So, you don't be nervous.
你也就大方一点嘛
Well,
对了
I didn't choose you
昨天选搭档的事情
as a partner yesterday.
没选你
I hope you won't be angry.
你也不要跟我怄气
Because I can only
毕竟我真的
choose one partner after all.
只好选一个嘛
Right?
对吧
If I have another chance,
以后有机会
I can apply to the captain
我跟队长申请一下
for being the partner of you.
咱俩搭档
No,
不用了
thanks.
谢谢
I understand that
我知道
you don't want to choose Miss Luo to be your partner.
你是不想跟骆警官搭档
Right?
是不是
I don't care who's my partner.
和谁搭档无所谓
And I didn't expect working here
我没有想过在这里
needs a partner.
需要搭档
He must think
他 他一定是觉得
he's not good enough for me.
配不上我
Everyone,
各位
look at Ronghua.
你们看看咱左哥的姿态
Who can be
你们谁能做到
as approachable like him?
这么地平易近人啊
He's a senior policeman,
都这么大岁数了
but still serving us water.
还给我们端茶倒水
Zhang,
老张
I don't agree with you.
瞧你说的
Brother Zuo is a real man
左哥是男子汉大丈夫
who knows when to be flexible and when to stand firm.
能屈能伸啊
He had witnessed all manner of things
当初在战场上
on the battlefield before.
什么世面没见过
Isn't it, Zuo?
是不是 老左
Zuo,
我说老左
the comrades in arms of you
你当年那群战友
have been officers
现在升官的升官
and directors.
当局长的当局长
Directors?
还当局长
If we can't solve the case,
案子办不明白
all of us can go home.
所长都别干了
I've just received the call from the Police Department.
我刚刚接到总局电话
They asked the murder case
问我文华饭店
in Van Hwa Hotel.
凶杀案的情况
Was the case filed
现在这个案子
in the Forth Station House?
是在四所立的案吧
Yes.
是
Because the case happened in our administrative area,
案子发生在我们辖区
so, it was filed in the Forth Station House.
所以是四所立的案
How is the case going?
有什么进展吗
I
我
am urging them
正 正在督促他们
to overcome difficulties.
正 正在克服
So, we don't have any clues, right?
那就是没有进展呗
How about other police stations?
其他警察所呢
Was there any information from residents?
有市民提供情报吗
Mr. Feng,
冯科长
the Second Station House
我们二所
doesn't have information.
没什么消息
Can I make a statement in this circumstance?
这种情况我能说吗
Do you have clues?
你有进展
It seems that I won't let you talk.
好像我压着你说似的
Speak your mind and use your own judgment.
有啥说啥 自己看着办
Mr. Feng,
冯科长
I've investigated the background of the Mr. and Mrs. Meng.
我查过孟氏夫妻的情况
They had a daughter indeed,
他们确实有个女儿
whose name is Meng Duoci.
叫做孟多慈
I'd checked
我到孟家查看过
the clothes of her
孟多慈的衣服
which were the same as the clothes in crime scene.
跟案发现场
The clothes
女孩儿的衣服
have similar size.
尺寸相似
And 3 of them
其中有三件
are the same brand.
是相同品牌的
I'd asked the Nanyang Model Private School
我也问了她就读的
she attended.
南洋模范私立中小学
The time of her truancy is the same as
她旷课的时间
the check-in time
跟入住文华饭店的时间
in Van Hwa Hotel.
是一致的
So, I suppose that
所以我推测
Meng Duoci lived in
孟多慈是跟父母
the same room with her parents.
住在同一个房间
And she probably
而且她很有可能
was the witness.
是目击者
Why didn't you report
这 这么重要的线索
such an important clue
你怎么
to Mr. Feng earlier?
怎么不早和冯科长说啊
Continue.
接着说
There had a murder case 2 months before,
两个月前
in which the victim's throat
发生过一起凶杀案
was cut, too.
死者也是被割喉
The conditions
各方面情况
were similar to
跟文华饭店的凶杀案
the case in Van Hwa Hotel.
是高度相似的
So, I doubt that
所以我怀疑
the murderer is the same.
凶手是同一个人
I think it is
我想把调查重心
the key to investigation.
放在这里
Didn't you learn about the condition
你们调查案子之前
before investigating the case?
不先了解清楚情况吗
The murderer of the former case
那桩凶杀案的凶手
had already been executed by shooting.
已经被枪决了
Really?
这么快
Or, wait for you?
不然呢 等你查
The Police Department attaches importance to the case,
总局很重视这个案子
because the victim was renowned before
毕竟受害人
after all.
有些社会名望
The Fourth Station House,
四所
prepare the materials
准备一下资料
and hand the case over to the Shiliupu Police Station.
移交分局
Yes, Chief.
是
Over.
散会
Zuo.
老左
Yes.
在
Do the new officers of the Fourth Station House
给你四所的新警员
work hard?
好用吗
Yes.
好用
They worked very hard.
非常好用
I felt sorry since
分给你的都是最后几名
you were given the bottom of them.
我多少有点儿过意不去
Don't talk like that.
别这么说
I'm not a
我老左不是那种
picky person.
挑三拣四的人
I won't trouble the leaders.
不给上面添 添麻烦
That's good.
那就好
Then, train them carefully.
那就好好管教
Yes.
是
The Police Department will shut down a bunch of
年底总局会撤一拨
useless police stations at the end of the year.
没有用的警察所
Pay attention to this.
你自己有点儿数啊
And tomorrow morning,
还有最迟明天早上
show me all
我要看到
the materials related to the murder case
文华饭店凶杀案的
in Van Hwa Hotel.
全部档案
OK.
是
I've attended so many meetings
开过这么多次会
and every time I don't have a seat
这么多个所长
while others
就我左荣华
always have.
连张椅子都没有
I'll bring a chair next time.
下次我给你带把椅子
Is the chair the key point?
我担心的是椅子吗
I'm worrying about the future of the Fourth Station.
我担心的是四所的未来
I didn't feel your concern.
您哪担心了
The murder case in Van Hwa Hotel
文华饭店凶杀案
will be handed over to the Shiliupu Police Station.
准备移交给分局了
It's an important case.
这是个重大案件
Both the Shiliupu Police Station and the Police Department
从总局到分局
are attaching importance to it.
都非常重视
Mr. Feng
冯科长呢
will investigate the case in person.
准备亲自来抓这个案件
From now on,
从今天开始
the case has nothing to do
这个案子
with us.
和大家就没什么关系了
The materials and clues
这些资料呢
will be handed over to Mr. Feng myself.
我会亲自交给冯科长
However, we have another task.
但是 大家都不要放松
From now on,
从现在开始
the case of abduction
这个诱拐案
is the key task of us.
就是我们重点要抓的
Everyone should work hard.
大家一定要继续努力
You get me?
明白了吗
Got you.
明白
We have a new clue
少女诱拐案
about the abduction case.
有了新的线索
There is a suspect
最近在西林路的
of the abduction case
凤凰舞厅
number 013.
疑似一名
He frequently appears
零三一号少女诱拐案
in the Fenghuang Dance Hall.
嫌疑人频繁进出
The dance hall is located in
凤凰舞厅在华界
the border
但是紧挨着
between us and French Concession.
法租界的分界线
The suspect possibly
嫌疑人很有可能
hides in the French Concession.
会往法租界里躲
Because he knows
知道我们在租界
that we can't catch him
没有执法权
without right.
不敢进去抓他呗
He exactly knows that
就是因为知道
he can escape the law
跨进了租界
in French Concession.
可以逍遥法外
So, people who violate the law
这些在华界犯了案的人
will flee to the French Concession.
总往法租界里躲
And we must arrest him
所以我们必须要赶在
before he
他跨过那条线之前
crosses the border.
抓住他
Captain,
队长
what if he crosses the border?
那万一他跨过去了呢
Then we can't catch him.
那肯定不能抓
If the French are angry in Police Service,
警务处那帮洋人闹起来
none of us will be better off.
咱谁都好不了
Try our best and we can do that.
尽全力就不可能有万一
Everyone puts on the daily clothes
所有人换便服
and carries the identification of police.
带好警员证
Someone must stay here.
另外 四所不能空着
Xiang Yuansheng, you stay here.
今天向远生你留守
I don't agree.
我不留守四所
Why?
你凭什么不留守
I came here by all manner of means
我托关系来四所
to catch the suspect.
是为了立功的
And this case provides me a good chance.
这么好的立功机会
I must go with you.
我必须参加
Who do you think you're?
你谁啊
Do you know
你知道嫌疑人
how sly the suspect is?
有多狡猾吗
We've made efforts and
你知道我们
tried for half a month
付出多少辛苦
without catching a suspect.
半个月都抓不到人
How could you catch him?
你去就能抓着
I can catch him
只要他在
as long as he is there.
我就能抓到
Bai.
二白
You mean that
你的意思是
you'll catch him if you go with us?
只要你去就一定能抓到
OK.
好
I believe you this time.
我相信你一次
But I have to say
但我提前说好
in advance.
如果你去抓不住的话
If you can't catch him,
不管你是托谁的关系
you won't
来的四所
have another chance
这是你第一次行动
no matter who you can rely on.
也是最后一次
You get me?
明白吗
Anyone else
其他人还有什么
has any ideas?
要说的吗
If you don't have,
没有的话
I'll make arrangements.
我就布置任务了
When we arrive at the Fenghuang Dance Hall,
到了凤凰舞厅
Bai keeps the main entrance of the hall,
二白守舞厅正门外面
and puts on the clothes of rickshaw driver.
换黄包车的衣服
Dongbao and Hongfa,
冬宝 鸿发
do you prepare the daily clothes?
你们的便服准备好了吗
Yes.
准备了
I've prepared 4,
我准备了四套
and I can play many roles.
让我假扮成什么都可以
Only need one.
只需要一套
OK.
好
Bai is the leader.
二白你负责
Minmin,
珉敏
you are in a group with Xiang Yuansheng.
你跟向远生一组
You are the leader
你负责
of the group.
你是组长
Yes.
是
This is the first cooperation of us.
所有人第一次行动
We should collaborate with each other
相互配合好
without causing trouble.
不要出乱子
You get me?
明白吗
Got you.
明白
Change clothes now.
换衣服
Do you have any idea
想好你一会儿
about what to wear?
穿啥了吗
Of course the clothes make me cool.
那不得穿板正点儿
Mr. Xiang.
向警官
What're you doing here without changing clothes?
不换衣服在这儿干吗呢
So, I'll change first.
你不换 那我
The captain
不是 队长着急
is waiting for us.
换衣服出任务
You.
你
Thank you.
谢谢
Who does she thank to?
她谢谁
I don't know.
不知道
Whoever.
别想了
Change the clothes.
换衣服 换衣服 换衣服
Mr. Xiang,
向警官
don't you think
你穿这套西服去抓人
it's too exaggerating to wear the suit?
是不是有点儿太浪费了
I don't have any other clothes.
我没有别的衣服
You should buy some
没有别的衣服
if you don't have.
那就记得买一身
Miss Luo,
骆警官
do you have a boyfriend?
你谈朋友了吗
Will you like a boyfriend
那你喜不喜欢
like Mr. Xiang?
向警官这样的
No.
不喜欢
He has no compassion.
太冷漠
What about me?
我 我
I'm compassionate.
我热情啊 我
This is the first action of us
咱们第一次行动
with wearing daily clothes.
又是便服
Everyone gets ready.
所有人准备好
Be relaxed
放松一点儿
in case of identity disclosure.
别让人发现
Move.
出发
Yes.
是
Hurry.
快点儿
Then I won't prepare the food.
那我就不准备饭了
Take care of yourself.
都注意安全
They're carrying out the task
都出去忙了
while we three are left.
就剩咱们仨了
Enjoy our leisure,
乐得清闲
right?
是不是
Drink up.
喝完了这
A roasted sweet potato, please.
老板 一个地瓜
Here you're.
来 给
OK.
老板 好了
Mr. Xiang,
向警官
Let's change another place.
我们换个地方吧
It costs too much.
这个地方太贵了
We're here to carry out the task.
我们是来执行任务的
And this is the best observation point.
这是最合适的观测点
Wait me for a moment.
你在这儿等我一下
Good morning, lady.
你好 女士
Good morning.
你好
I would like a cup of coffee.
我想要一杯咖啡
OK, wait a minute.
好的 您稍等
I only order a cup of coffee.
我只点了一杯咖啡
You can have a drink.
你喝吧
I don't like its taste.
我喝不惯
Don't worry about the money.
你不用担心钱的事情
Although it costs much.
虽然这个咖啡有点贵
I'm the leader of the group.
但是我是组长
So, I'll bear the cost.
我会负责的
Well.
对了
Chen Hao told me that
陈浩说执行任务
we have a budget.
是有经费的
Pardon?
什么经费
It's weird that
你坐在这里不吃不喝
you drink nothing and just sit here.
很奇怪
We have to spend the money
这些钱是可以花掉的
to pretend our identities.
必要的伪装
And,
还有
you look very nervous,
你现在看起来很紧张
which makes us unnatural.
这样很容易暴露破绽
Am I?
我现在看起来很紧张吗
If you don't like coffee,
喝不惯咖啡
you can take a cake.
就点个蛋糕吃吧
That's what we should do
这样才像是来咖啡馆
in the cafe.
会做的事儿
A cake of chocolate or fruits?
巧克力的还是水果的
Chocolate.
巧克力
Is here the right place?
是这儿吗
Yes.
是这儿
I've investigated that
我查到他最近
he had a business in this dance hall.
在这间舞厅谈买卖
Move.
行动了
Sun Hongfa, he isn't the suspect.
孙鸿发 不是
They moved.
他们行动了
Remain seated.
坐着别动
Miss Luo
骆警官
You catch the wrong person.
抓错人了
What's wrong with you?
你怎么搞的
The member of them
最近送的人
is fewer and fewer.
是越来越少了
I'm so sorry.
不好意思 哥
Will you do it well?
你行不行
I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
You'll give me two days.
你容我两天 两天后
I'll make you satisfied.
包您满意
Hurry up.
抓紧点儿啊
I will.
好嘞 哥
Sanyou.
三友
See that?
看到了吧
This is the criterion.
就按这个找
OK.
好嘞 好嘞
Hurry up.
快点儿
Got you.
知道了
Get out of the way.
让开
That's him.
就是他
Wait.
等会儿
Chen Hao.
陈浩
Why are the policemen of the Fourth Station House all here?
怎么四所的都在这儿啊
Follow them.
跟上
Stop.
站住
Don't run.
别动了
Are you an octopus?
八爪鱼
You hold me so tightly.
抱着人就不撒手
Are you a real policeman?
你学过怎么当警察吗你
Shut up.
少说话吧你
You aren't a real policeman.
你也算警察
You're so rude.
耍流氓
I've been shouting from behind
我在后面这么喊
but couldn't get through to you guys.
也喊不住你们几个
After all this hustle, only catch a petty thief.
忙活这么半天抓一小偷
What?
什么
Isn't he the suspect of the abduction case?
他不是诱拐犯
I'm not.
你才诱拐犯呢你
You're a thief anyway.
那你也是小偷
He rammed a person.
撞人了
Get out of the way.
让开
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
The front is the French Concession.
前边是法租界
We police don't have right
我们警察没有权力
to catch suspects there.
在这儿抓人
It's okay if I'm not a policeman, right?
不是警察就可以了吧
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Are you crazy, Xiang Yuansheng?
疯了 向远生
Don't come over.
你别过来啊
Are you okay?
队长你没事吧
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
They're catching the suspect.
听说抓人了这是
Don't come over.
别过来
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Get out of here.
出来
Get out of here, Xiang Yuansheng.
出来 向远生
Go back.
回去
Take him out.
把人带出来 你出来
Get out of here, Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生 出来
Hurry.
快
Get out of here.
出来
Hurry up.
快点儿
Hurry up out.
快 出来
Help.
救命啊
You are the policeman of China.
你是华界警察
I'm not a policeman.
我不是警察
Sorry.
不好意思
He's my team member.
他是我的队员
I'm the supervisor of the Police Service
我是公董局
from Shanghai French Concession Municipal Council.
警务处督察员
Who are you?
您是哪位
Nice to meet you.
您好
I'm Chen Hao, the captain policeman of
我是上海市公安局
the Fourth Station House
十六铺分局第四警察所
of Shiliupu Police Station in Shanghai.
队长陈浩
How could your member arrest a suspect
你的警员招呼都不打
without our permission?
就进来抓人
Don't you know
不知道华界警察
Chinese police
在这里面
haven't right to arrest suspects here?
是没有执法权的吗
I'm not.
我的警员证已经
Sorry.
对不起
He's a police cadet.
他是实习警察
And he knows little.
不太懂规矩
You can't bring the suspect back.
犯人你没有权力带走
What's more,
另外
that policeman has to go
我要扣押
with me.
这个动手的警员
It's impossible.
这不可能
Captain Chen.
陈队长
This is the regulation here.
这是按条例办事
I know the regulations.
我知道你说的条例
But I can't leave him here
但我不可能因为这些
because of
狗屁倒灶的条例
the nonsense rules.
就让你扣我的人
You have the right to
你有权向公董局
file a complaint to the Shanghai French Concession Municipal Council.
提出申诉
Take him away.
把人带走
Don't move.
别动 干什么
I need to file a complaint now.
我现在就要申诉
This road isn't in French Concession.
这条路还不属于法租界
It is.
这已经划进了法租界
We caught the suspect
那小子被摁住的时候
here.
在这儿
Watch it clearly.
看清楚了
And there is French Concession.
那才是法租界
The entrance door is under renovating.
这个大门还没有修好
The road won't belong to the French Concession
这大门一天不修好
until the
一天就不属于
renovation is finished.
你们的地方
Moreover,
再说了
we're in the territory of China now.
人现在已经在华界了
If you take him,
只要你抓人
you'll violate the regulations.
就是越界
Last month,
上个月
Shanghai French Concession Municipal Council
公董局已经和
had signed an agreement
上海市政府
with Shanghai Municipal Government.
签订了协议
This road belongs to French Concession now.
这条路现在属于法租界
It never belongs to
这从来就不属于
French Concession.
你们的地方
Captain Chen,
陈队长
you're against the rules.
你们在知法犯法
What are you doing?
你又在做什么
The suspect had abducted
这小子拐走了
4 girls.
四名女孩儿
Mind your own job.
管好你自己的地盘
A murder case happened
前段时间
in Van Hwa Hotel,
文华饭店的凶杀案
which is your administrative area.
可就在你们的管辖
Have you arrested him?
人抓到了吗
Mr. Meng is the excellent taxpayer
孟先生是我们法租界
in French Concession.
最优秀的纳税人
You'll soon receive the complaints hotline
等着公董局的
from Shanghai French Concession Municipal Council.
投诉电话吧
Wait.
等等
I buy all your scallion cakes.
葱油饼我全要了
OK.
好嘞
Captain Chen,
陈队长
please apply to me
下次再进法租界
for the permission
哪怕只是买个葱油饼
even if you just want to buy a scallion cake.
也麻烦提前跟我申请
Let's go.
收队
You also know it is a concession.
你也知道是租啊
You'll return the place
既然是租
one day.
迟早要还
OK, thank you.
好 谢谢您
Let's go back.
回去
Go.
走
Mr. Xiang is agile.
向警官这身手可真好
You arrest the suspect with a punch.
一拳给他撂那儿了
If I were him,
这要打在我身上
I can't stand up.
那我就窝那儿起不来了
Is it true that Mr. Xiang
向警官
failed the entrance exam of police
真的是考不上警察
so that he got in by relationship?
才走后门进来的
It can't be true.
向警官那身手那么好
Mr. Xiang has cat-like reflexes.
不可能考不上警察吧
Why does it become tighter
他这绳子
as I pull it?
怎么越拉越紧呢
Let me see.
我看看
Sorry, sorry.
哥 哥 哥
It hurts.
疼 疼 疼
It's tighter indeed.
是紧了
It really hurts.
疼 疼 轻点儿
I've seen this
这个我见过
on the newspaper.
在报纸上
It's called
好像叫
sailors' knot.
水手结
Only naval sailors can do this.
海军才会
How could he
他
have something to do
他跟海军
with the navy?
能扯上什么关系
I know that
我知道了
villagers use knots like this
我们村里面绑猪
to tight the pigs.
它也是这么绑的
Enough.
你别扯了
Though I haven't seen this before,
我没见过猪跑
I have my own judgment.
还没吃过猪肉吗
What's your opinion?
你看啥呢
I know.
这 这我知道
What?
你知道啥
He's right.
他 他说得对
Oh, come on.
对个屁啊对
I'll handle the problem
离开四所之前
before I leave the station.
我会解决这件事儿
You can tell other policemen that
你可以告知其他警员
they won't be involved.
我不会牵连四所的
Be a policeman as you like.
想当就当
Give up being as you don't like.
不想当就不当
Doesn't the word POLICE
警察这两个字对你来说
mean anything to you?
一点意义都没有吗
You are not wanting to be policeman
你根本就不是
sincerely.
来当警察的
What are you really up to?
你到底想干吗
First, you say you're in Shanghai to take in the sights,
一会儿说来上海看风景
and then suddenly,
一会儿又说
you're talking about becoming a policeman to win honour.
想当警察立功
Who sent you here?
到底谁派你来上海的
Why can you be a policeman in the Fourth Station House?
又是谁派你来四所的
What happened, Captain?
怎么了 队长
Car ramming again.
又撞了
Answer my question.
回答我
No one sent me.
没有谁派我来
It is a break of being a policeman.
当警察算是个插曲吧
I won't stay here
我不会在四所
so long.
待太长时间
You are a member of us
你一天不走
before you leave.
一天就是四所的警员
You're going to
你的横冲直撞
hurt everyone here
会害了这里
with your rampage.
所有当警察的人
Although the Fourth Station House isn't big,
四所不大
we have own regulations.
但是也有原则
You've said that
报到那天
the principle of being a policeman
我记得陈队长说
is upholding the justice
警察的原则是匡扶正义
and protecting people when I firstly arrived here.
保护百姓吧
Yes.
是
But I don't let you.
但是没让你
I know better the meanings of
我比这里大部分人
disciplinary, obedience
都更加明白
and principle
什么是纪律 服从
than anyone else.
还有规则
That's why you disobey my words?
明白还拉都拉不住吗
It isn't
只是有些东西在我这里
my principle.
根本就不算是规则
I've learned a new word
今天跟陈队长
from you.
还学了一个新词
Nonsense.
狗屁倒灶
You don't need to worry about me just now.
其实你刚才不用管我的
As the captain,
我是队长
it's my duty to protect my members,
有责任维护我的队员
especially on this matter.
尤其是这件事情上